《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
他是誰
Who's that?
我是鮑勃·柯克蘭  國土安全局的
Bob Kirkland, Homeland Security.
-我認識你嗎  -不  但我認識你
- Do I know you? - No, but I know you.
全部都拿回來
Get me everything.
簡把很多關于血腥約翰的線索都關聯到了一起
Jane made a lot of Red John connections here.
很好
This is good.
為什么這還扯上了國土安全問題
Why is this a homeland security issue?
這里面的內情復雜
It's complicated.
我是里斯本探員  這位是簡  加調局的
Agent Lisbon, Jane, CBI.
抱歉  只有聯調局的人能進
Sorry, F.B.I. personnel only.
我們也不想來
Uh, we don't want to be here, either,
是別人邀請我們來的
but we were invited.
麻煩你告訴里德·史密斯探員
Uh, could you tell Agent Reede Smith
我們應約到了
that we're here as requested?
你認為史密斯意圖何在
What do you think Smith wants?
我不知道  你怎么看
I don't know. What do you think?
每次要見血腥約翰案的疑犯
Every time we go to see one of these Red John suspects,
我都會很急躁
I get edgy.
是嗎  看不出來
Really? Can't tell.
真的嗎
Really?
簡  里斯本  多謝前來
Jane, Lisbon. Thanks for coming.
誰愿意錯過這個呢
Miss this? Who could say no?
我們能幫些什么  史密斯探員
How can we be of help, Agent Smith?
我們發現一具尸體
We caught a body.
我感覺你們會有興趣
I thought it might interest you.
何出此言呢
And why would you say that?
你看了就知道了
You tell me.
他是本杰明·馬克思
This is Benjamin Marx.
就是你活埋的那個人
The guy you buried alive.
出自第四季 第二十三集
恕我糾正一下
Excuse me.
是我活埋的那個殺人兇手
The killer I buried alive.
而且我最后放他出來了
And I did let him out-- eventually.
算你眼力準  尸體很難辨認
Not bad. That's a tough I.D.,
大部分臉都燒毀了
considering most of his face is burnt off.
你覺得他身上發生了什么事
What do you think happened to him?
你是聯調局探員
You're the F.B.I.
你肯定已經知道了吧
I-I'm sure you have the answers already.
好吧
Okay.
那你說說我都發現了什么
Tell me what I've come up with.
首先  你肯定注意到了
Well, the first thing you'd notice
他被刑訊逼供了
is that he was tortured--
被人用火燒  還用別的什么兇器
with fire and whatever it is people use
砍下了他的手指
to cut someone's thumbs off.
那我認為兇手是想逼他說出什么呢
And what do I think he was tortured for?
你肯定認為兇手是為了獲得施虐的快感
Well, your guess would be sadistic pleasure,
但你錯了
but you'd be wrong.
兇手折磨他  更有可能是為了獲取信息
More likely he was tortured for information--
他不知道的信息
Information that he didn't have.
你怎么知道他不知道
How do you know he didn't have it?
因為他如果知道的話
Because if he had it,
那個兇手只要燒掉他的半邊臉他就招了
the killer would only have had to burn off half his face.
我還有其他什么想法沒
What else do I think?
刑訊逼供需要時間
Well, whoever did the torturing took their time,
所以你會想到他們選用了一個僻靜的地方
so you would reason that they had somewhere private to do it.
沒錯
Right.
我相信你看到了
And I'm sure you saw
死者的腿上有點黏糊糊的東西
the, uh, sticky stuff on the leg of the victim,
可能已經送去化驗了
probably sent it off to the lab.
等三天后化驗結果出來
And in three days they'll tell you
他們會告訴你那是松樹樹汁  那就說得通了
that it's pine sap, which makes sense,
因為他的鞋底嵌進了一根
Because there's a broken pine needle
斷裂的松針
wedged into the sole of his shoe.
對  我看到了
Yeah, I see.
所以最終你會得出結論
Eventually you'd come to the conclusion
他是被人囚禁在某個樹林里
that he was kept in the woods someplace
然后被殺害棄尸至此的
before he was killed and dumped here.
棒極了
Nice.
那為何要叫我們來這里  史密斯探員
Uh, why are we here, Agent Smith?
馬克思受審期間被保釋
Marx was out on bail while he stood trial.
事態對他也蠻有利的
Things were looking good for him, too.
你刑訊逼供讓他認罪
I mean, you tortured him into a confession,
請有個好點的律師
so a little good lawyering,
再加上一點運氣  他就沒事了
a little luck, and he could walk.
那樣就你就不好受了吧  簡
Bet that really chapped your hide, huh, Jane?
一點沒有
Not at all.
這就是聯調局能得出的最好結論了嗎
That's the best theory the F.B.I. can come up with?
你們認為是簡殺了本杰明·馬克思還燒掉了他的臉
That Jane killed Benjamin Marx and burned his face off?
我們得考慮所有可能性
We're exploring every angle.
他是其中一個
He's an angle.
如果我想殺掉本杰明·馬克思
Listen. If I wanted to kill Benjamin Marx,
上次就動手了
I would have done it the first time.
他是專騙孤兒寡母錢的反社會分子
He was a sociopath that stole from widows and orphans,
他是罪有應得
and he got what he deserved.
但我沒殺他
But I didn't do it.
等著看吧
We'll see.
好啊
Yes, we will.
多謝前來
Thanks for coming.
-怎么回事  簡  -沒事
- What's going on, Jane? - Nothing.
-告訴我  -我說了沒事
- Tell me. - I said it's nothing.
你從來不會沒事
It's never nothing with you.
你認為史密斯是血腥約翰嗎
Do you think Smith is Red John?
有可能
Possibly.
如果他不是血腥約翰  那他就是個蠢貨
Well, if he isn't Red John, he's an idiot
居然認為你跟馬克思的死有關
for thinking you could have anything to do with Marx's death.
他也不是完全錯了
He's not completely wrong.
當然  我沒有殺本杰明·馬克思
I mean, I-I didn't kill Benjamin Marx,
但是我可能間接害他被殺了
but I might have gotten him killed.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
■
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：灰灰是菇涼  丁丁  王小麥  Michael  那時花開
■
超感警探
第六季
第四集
■
時間軸：兜兜兜爹  Sagelibra   校對：灰灰是菇涼
第六季
第四集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇涼   精校&總監：灰灰是菇涼
好了  不準有任何隱瞞  快說
Okay, no more secrets. Spill it now.
我在分析血腥約翰案名單的時候很在意保密問題
I was concerned with security when I was working my list of Red John suspects.
你都保密到走火入魔了
Obsessively secretive.
隨你怎么說
Yeah, well, you say "tomato,"
但是我知道有人想要我的信息
but I knew there were people that needed that information.
所以我就往板子上寫上了
So I planted what you would call
你說的那種"錯誤信息"
misinformation on my crime board.
看到你的案件分析板的人
So whoever saw your crime board
就得到了血腥約翰案的七名疑犯名單
got the list of the seven Red John suspects.
但那是錯的疑犯名單
But they would be the wrong suspects.
正是如此  而且起效了
Exactly. And it worked.
有人闖進了我的辦公室
Someone broke into my office.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
我設了個小陷阱  牙簽被人弄斷了
Well, I set a trap, and it was sprung.
現在那個人手上有那份名單
Now this person has a fake list of Red John suspects,
而本杰明·馬克思在那份名單上
and Benjamin Marx was on that list.
這么說有人在拷問和謀殺那些
So somebody is torturing and killing
你的假名單上的人
the people on your fake list.
沒必要說得那么絕對
Whoa, whoa. N-not necessarily.
有人拷問并謀殺了我名單上的一個人
Someone tortured and killed one person from my list.
但從理論上講  他的死可能出于任何原因
But theoretically, his death could be about anything.
他可不是個好人
He wasn't a nice man.
我反復在思考這件事想搞明白
I am trying to wrap my mind around this.
你將七個無辜的人的生命置于危險之中
You put the lives of seven innocent people in danger.
不  他們沒一個人是無辜的
No. None of them are innocent.
馬克思詐騙了成千上百的人
Marx defrauded hundreds of people...
他為了掩蓋這事  殘忍殺害了一個人
Then he brutally murdered someone to cover it up.
我向你保證  里斯本
I assure you, Lisbon...
名單上的所有人都是惡人
All of these men are very bad.
只不過他們碰巧不是血腥約翰罷了
They just don't happen to be Red John.
你認為會是真的血腥約翰闖入這里
Do you think the real Red John could have broken in here
殺了馬克思嗎
and killed Marx?
除了我們  血腥約翰是唯一一個
Well, Red John is the only person besides us
知道真的疑犯名單的人
that knows the real list of suspects,
因此他也是唯一一個沒有動機做此事的人
so he is the only person that has no motive to do this.
那闖進來的是誰
Then who broke in here?
我不知道
I don't know.
是一個便于進出這里  有很多手段與權力的人
Someone with easy access, a lot of resources and power.
是聯調局的  他們一直
The F.B.I. They've been wanting
想要染指血腥約翰案
to get their hands on the Red John case for a while.
國土安全局接手的時候他們很不高興
They were not happy when Homeland Security took over.
對
True.
我一直懷疑聯調局里有人在監視我
You know, I've always suspected the F.B.I. are watching me.
私下里
Personally.
雖然聽起來很像是太多疑了
As paranoid as it sounds,
但這倒是解釋了他們是如何拿到馬克思案子的
it would explain how they got the Marx case.
但他們為什么要拷問他
But why would they do this to him?
我們該怎么著手
And how do we proceed?
我不能就直接去聯調局問他們
I can't just go to the F.B.I. and ask them
是不是他們殺了馬克思
if they killed Marx.
如果聯調局在監視我
If the F.B.I. Has been watching me,
我打賭一定是加調局的某位高層
I'll bet that someone very high up in the CBI
批準了此事  至少同意此事
authorized it, or at least went along with it.
我得找他們談談
I need to talk to them.
伯特侖  但顯然你不能問他
Bertram. But you obviously can't ask him.
那就找瑪德琳·海托華
Madeleine Hightower then.
海托華
Hightower?
她已經不在加調局當事三年了
She hasn't run the CBI in three years.
你覺得她還能獲得什么信息
What kind of information do you think she still has access to?
就算她能  為什么她愿意跟你分享
And if so, why would she share it with you?
血腥約翰想殺她
Well, Red John tried to kill her.
她肯定會幫我的
She's gonna want to help me.
除非她認為此事錯在你
Unless she blames you.
我還是打給她吧
Eh. I'm gonna call her.
好吧
Fine.
你今天打算做些什么
Oh. What do you have planned for the day?
你沒什么正式的案子要辦  對吧
You don't officially have a case, do you?
就放松下吧
You can relax.
去按摩一下  做個美甲
Get a massage, mani/pedi.
不要
No.
我要去找你名單上的六個人
I have to go and offer protection
向他們提供保護  而你  要給我那六個人的名字
to the six people on your list, which you are going to give me.
我原本還盼著你去做按摩呢
I was hoping you'd opt for the massage.
真不敢相信
Oh, I can't believe it.
終于把他哄睡著了
Finally got him back to sleep.
干得好  瑞斯比先生
Good job, Mr. Rigsby.
接下來的一小時我們也不用出門工作
And we don't have to leave for work for another hour.
我們怎么來打發時間呢
What are we gonna do to pass the time?
還不知道呢  瑞斯比夫人
Well, I don't know, Mrs. Rigsby.
不要啊
Oh... don't.
是里斯本
It's Lisbon.
讓她等一會吧
She can wait 10 minutes.
里斯本
Lisbon.
肯定有重要的事  快接吧
It must be important. You should get it.
早啊  頭兒
Morning, boss.
你和瑞斯比負責這四個
You and Rigsby take these four.
我負責海爾巴和李
I'll take Haibach and Lee.
海爾巴不是那個圣華金河殺手案里的嗎
Isn't Haibach the guy from the Panzer case
拍了很多小女孩照片那個
with all the photos of the little girls?
是的  我之前跟他打過交道
Yeah. I've dealt with him once before,
所以他可能愿意跟我談
so maybe he'll be more likely to come with me.
強奸指控  販毒指控
Rape charges, drug charges,
販賣人口指控
human trafficking charges.
沒搞錯吧  我們要幫助這些人
Really? We're gonna help these guys?
這就是我們的工作  我們無權選擇
That's the job. We don't get to pick and choose.
我們要警告這些人他們現在有生命危險
We need to warn these men that their lives are in danger
并為他們提供保護
and offer them protection.
趕緊開工吧
Now get on it.
今天早晨我一直在看她刷牙
And I was watching her brush her teeth this morning,
她竟然刷了整整兩分鐘
and she does the full two minutes,
完全按照牙醫要求的那樣
just like the dentist says.
要是換了別人  我早就覺得煩了
The wrong person, that could be really annoying,
但是今天  我覺得這樣挺好
but today I just thought, cool.
我這下半輩子都有她
I'm gonna be spending the rest of my life
-這副好牙相伴  明白嗎  -不明白
- with those really good teeth, you know? - Nope.
我的意思是  結婚比我想像得要好
M-my point is, marriage is even better than I thought.
除了
Except...
也不是什么大事  結婚才三天嘛
It's not a big deal. It's only been three days.
也挺有意思的  真的
It's sort of funny, really.
我  我們還沒那個過
W-we haven't done it yet.
結婚以后
As a married couple.
酒店那晚呢
What about at the hotel?
婚禮后  我送你們上了馬車
After the wedding. I got you that carriage.
是的  我們當時都不省人事了
Yeah, we passed out.
那天太激動了
It was a very emotionally draining day.
-再加上我們喝了很多酒  -也是
- Plus we drank too much. - Right.
而且第二天我們還要工作
Then we had to work the next day.
而且那之后  薩拉一直在洛杉磯開會
And since then, Sara's at a conference in L.A.,
本就一直從早到晚由我們帶著
so we've had Ben every day, morning and night.
我在網上看過一篇研究報告
You know, I read a study on the Internet.
上面說女人一旦結婚之后
It said women lose interest in sex
就會馬上變得性冷淡
almost immediately after marriage.
達爾文主義者的觀點
It's Darwinian.
格蕾斯絕不可能  她總是非常...
Nah, not Grace. She's always been super into...
我的意思是  我不信  不可能是真的
M-my point is, I don't believe it. It's not true.
我只是跟你說我在網上看到的論點
I'm just telling you what the Internet said.
里克·多特  加調局的  開門
Rick Dort? CBI. Open up.
在網上誰想說什么都行
Anyone can say anything on the Internet.
不一定是真的
Doesn't mean it's true.
什么事
Yeah?
多特先生嗎
Mr. Dort?
我們是加調局的瑞斯比和周探員
Agents Rigsby and Cho from the CBI.
我們想跟你談談
We want to talk to you about--
舉起手來  否則打爆你的頭
Hands in the air, or I'll shoot you in the head.
伙計  別開槍
Hey, man, don't shoot.
我們有理由相信你有生命危險
We have reason to believe your life's in danger.
我們是來給你提供警方保護的
We came to offer police protection.
什么
What?
你現在有生命危險
Your life is in danger.
是這事
It is?
你們不是因為冰毒  別的事
You're not here about the meth... other thing?
冰[別]的事
The meh... other thing?
沒什么別的事
There is no other thing.
口誤了
Slip of the tongue.
趕緊出來
Get out of the pool.
格蕾斯  你有點憔悴
Hey, Grace. You look a little peaked.
我知道你為什么一直
I found out why you haven't been able
聯系不上海托華了
to get in touch with Hightower.
為什么  告訴我
What is it? Tell me.
我跟她姑姑通過電話  她說
I spoke to her aunt, and she said
海托華和孩子們出事了
Hightower and the kids had an accident.
他們都死了
They're dead.
什么  什么時候的事
What? When?
兩周前在墨西哥度假的時候
Two weeks ago on vacation in Mexico.
他們淹死了
They drowned.
為什么我們之前不知道
How come we didn't hear about it sooner?
很奇怪
It's very strange.
他們一直沒有找到尸體
Apparently, they never found the bodies,
當局已經停止了搜救工作
and authorities have called off the search and rescue.
你剛才說她姑姑叫什么
Wh-what did you say her aunt's name was?
露比  露比·海托華
Ruby. Ruby hightower.
我需要她的地址
Yeah, well, I-I'gonna need an address.
我得送點花去
I need to send her some flowers.
太不幸了
That's terrible.
我是鮑勃·柯克蘭
This is Bob Kirkland.
柯克蘭  我是聯調局的里德·史密斯探員
Kirkland. This is Agent Reede Smith, F.B.I.
有什么要幫忙的嗎  史密斯
What can I do for you, Smith?
我想是你需要我幫忙
I think it's what I can do for you.
我的上級讓我把正在查的
My superiors asked that I fill you in
一個案子的詳情告訴你
on a case I'm working.
跟派翠克·簡有關
It involves Patrick Jane.
說吧
I'm listening.
是一起謀殺綁架案
It's a murder/kidnapping thing.
死者名叫本杰明·馬克思
Vic's a guy named Benjamin Marx.
簡之前跟他打過交道
Jane dealt with him before.
用了一些  該怎么說呢
Used some... shall we say,
比較過分的方法讓他認罪了
over-the-top techniques to get Marx to confess?
聽起來像是簡會做的事
That sounds about right.
馬克思當時在受審  可能會被無罪釋放
Marx was on trial, could have gone free.
坦白說  我覺得可能是簡干的
Frankly, I like Jane for it.
他跟血腥約翰有過節
He's got a vigilante beef with Red John.
可能這案子跟他有關
Maybe this is his thing.
我覺得你猜得沒錯
I think you might be on to something.
-干得好  -謝謝
- Nice work. - Thanks.
還有  史密斯  有消息通知我
And, Smith? Keep me in the loop.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
什么事
Yes?
海托華女士
Mrs. Hightower?
節哀順變
I'm so sorry for your loss.
我以前跟你侄女瑪德琳共事過
I used to work with your niece Madeleine,
我希望能跟您談談
and, uh, well, I was hoping that maybe we could talk.
這是給您的
These are for you.
快請進
Oh, please come in.
謝謝你  花很漂亮
Thank you. They are very nice.
你最后一次見到你侄女是什么時候
When was the last time you saw your niece?
幾周之前  他們去度假之前
A few weeks ago, right before they went on vacation.
她們特意過來看我
They made a point to come and see me.
至少我有機會能跟她們告別
At least I got a chance to say good-bye.
是啊  真是這樣
Yeah, well, there-- there's that.
怎么了
What is it?
只是
Oh, it's just, uh...
我真希望我能有什么辦法
I just wish that there was some way I could...
讓她知道我的感受
let her know how I feel.
可以的
There is.
我的鄰居電腦技術很厲害
My neighbor is very good with the computer.
他在網上建了一個
He set up a private memorial site
私人追悼網站
on the Internet
只給朋友和家人悼念用
Just for friends and family.
我想看看
I'd love to see that.
好了  就是這個
Okay, here you go.
你能不能
Oh, d-do you mind?
我不太會用電腦
I'm not very good with computers.
當然  想說什么就說什么
Sure. Just say what you need to say.
這么寫
Write this.
死后
In death...
你會獲得新生
you have found new life...
我想站在山頂高喊
And I want to shout it from the mountaintops.
紀念瑪德琳
我內心深知
I know in my heart,
我最親愛的瑪德琳
dearest Madeleine...
當夕陽落下時
that when sunset comes,
你會在天堂的花園里
I will find you waiting for me...
等著我
in the heavenly gardens.
愛你的  派翠克
Love, Patrick.
說得太
Oh... that was, um...
太感人了
that's lovely.
很有詩意
Very poetical.
謝謝  我感覺好多了
Thank you. Feels a lot better.
我該走了
I should--I should go.
小可憐
Or, you poor lamb.
你有點喜歡她  是吧
You were a little sweet on her, weren't you?
加州  薩克拉門托市  理查德·海爾巴家
不行
No.
我記得你  跟我律師談去
I remember you. Talk to my lawyer.
海爾巴先生
Mr. Haibach.
不是你想的那樣  先聽我說完
It's not what you think. Just hear me out.
我想的是  你一直想給我安上個什么罪名
I think you've wanted to pin something on me for a long time.
我不是那么好欺負的  里斯本女士
I won't be your patsy, Ms. Lisbon.
是里斯本探員
It's Agent Lisbon.
我們有理由相信你有生命危險
And we have reason to believe that your life is in danger.
我來這是向你提供警方保護的
I am here to offer you police protection.
這么說如果我跟你走
So if I go with you,
不會有什么倒霉事了
nothing bad will happen to me?
聽著像是你們警察的老把戲了  里斯本探員
Sounds like police state trickery, Agent Lisbon.
斯塔西會以你們為榮的
The STASI would be proud.
前東德國家安全部
從法律和道義上講我都應該通知你
I am legally and morally bound to inform you that--
別在這裝什么道德高尚了
Please don't try to stake out the moral high ground here.
如果聽你的  我早就因為
If you had your way, I'd be in jail
莫須有的罪而蹲監獄了
for a crime I didn't commit.
這次還是聽我的吧
I think I'll take my chances.
怎么樣  簡
How's it going, Jane?
我剛拜訪了海托華的姑姑
I just visited with Hightower's aunt.
太讓人傷心了
That's so sad.
有查出什么東西嗎
Did you find anything out?
你覺得血腥約翰與此有關嗎
I mean, do you think Red John had anything to do with it?
我覺得沒有  和他的犯罪手法不一樣
I don't think so. Not his M.O.
你覺得只是一場意外嗎
So you think it's just an accident?
看起來是的  找人找的怎么樣了
Looks like it. How's the roundup going?
海爾巴不愿意跟我走  我覺得他有所隱瞞
Haibach wouldn't come with me. I think he's hiding something.
他那樣的人一般都會對女警
Well, a guy like that probably takes issue
有意見
with lady police.
應該說是對女性有意見
Ladies in general.
你說得對  我讓周和瑞斯比走一趟
Uh, you're right. You know what? I'll send Cho and Rigsby.
也可以不用
Or not.
他出事也不會有人在意的
Would the world really miss him if something happened?
這就是你我的不同之處
And that's the difference between you and me.
先掛了
And good-bye.
如果你也是加調局的  我要
If you are from CBI, I'm--
怎么回事
What happened?
我們來的時候門開著
We found the door open,
地上有血跡和啤酒瓶
blood and beer bottle on the floor.
海爾巴不見了  瑞斯比正在和鄰居問話
No Haibach. Rigsby's canvassing the neighbors.
這可糟了
This is bad.
未必
Not really.
這證實了有人正通過我的名單
Confirms the theory that someone is going through my list
尋找血腥約翰的猜想
trying to find Red John.
海爾巴被綁架了
Haibach has been abducted,
很有可能會被折磨致死
and he's probably gonna be tortured to death.
是啊  他今天晚上會挺難熬的
Yeah, he's in for a rough night.
我們得告訴史密斯和聯調局
And we have to tell Smith and the F.B.I.
他被綁架了  還有此案和馬克思案有關
that he's been taken and that it's connected to the Marx case.
-不行  不能說  -我們不能說謊
- No, we don't. - We can't lie.
我們一直在說謊
We do it all the time.
他總會理出頭緒的
He's gonna put it together eventually,
到時候結果只會更糟
and it'll be worse.
好吧  那就告訴他
Okay, fine. Tell him.
但是不要提名單的事
But do not mention the list.
就告訴他和一樁舊案有關的人失蹤了
Just tell him that someone else connected to an old case of ours has gone missing.
我同意
Agreed.
現在該怎么辦
What do we do now?
很快就知道了
I will have the answer for that very soon.
黑咖  奶咖
I have black, milk...
以及一杯加奶加糖的
and milk and sugar.
你不喝的我喝
I'll take whatever you don't want.
你總是這么細心嗎
You always this thorough?
我喜歡考慮周全
I like to cover all my bases.
加奶加糖的那杯
Milk and sugar.
謝謝
Thanks.
你說你有東西要給我
So you said you got something for me?
我之前跟你說的那個案子
There's been an interesting development
有了點有趣的進展
in that case I was telling you about.
又有一個和簡有關的人
Looks like another man's gone missing
失蹤了
that's connected with Jane.
一個叫理查德·海爾巴的
A, uh, Richard Haibach.
確實很有趣
That is interesting.
謝謝
Thank you.
雖然這跟我無關  但是
Look, it's none of my business, but, uh...
你和簡之間到底什么情況
can I ask what the deal is with you and Jane?
說來話長
Long story.
那隨便吧
Whatever.
我也不是要打聽什么
I'm not looking to pry.
這點很好
I like that.
我調查了你一下
I've done some research on you.
我嗎
On me?
沒錯  你作為探員很不錯
Yeah. You're a good agent.
非常坦白  正直
Real straight shooter.
你為什么要查我
Why would you research me?
我有其他事想跟你談談
I have some other business I want to discuss with you.
需要謹慎對待的事
Delicate business.
好  說吧
Okay. Shoot.
老虎  老虎
Tiger tiger.
啥
Huh?
老虎  老虎
Tiger tiger.
你在耍我嗎
What, are you messing with me?
那是什么東西  老虎  老虎
What--what is that? "Tiger tiger"?
你真不知道嗎
You really don't know?
知道什么
Know what?
沒什么  這是個測試
Nothing. That's a test.
好吧
Okay.
我完全一頭霧水  你想給我講講嗎
I'm totally in the dark here. You want to fill me in?
調查血腥約翰的時候
While investigating Red John,
國土安全局開始懷疑
Homeland Security's begun to suspect
在加州執法部門里存在著一個
the existence of a powerful secret organization
強大的秘密組織
within California law enforcement.
警方  加調局  司法部
Police, CBI, D.O.J.
我們認為都是高層人物
Strictly high-level, we think.
他們是干什么的
What do they do?
臟活
They do dirt.
他們互相掩護
They protect each other with major cover-ups,
逃脫謀殺嫌疑
get away with murder.
那老虎又是什么
What's the tiger thing?
我們覺得那是暗號
We think that's the password.
真詭異
Spooky.
血腥約翰是其中一員嗎
Is Red John a member?
現在還不好說
It's too soon to tell.
那簡呢
What about Jane?
我們只是剛理出頭緒
We're just starting to put this thing together.
我們想在聯調局里找人合作
We're looking for partners within the F.B.I.
級別較低的
Lower level guys that...
我們確定可以相信的人
we're sure we can trust.
也就是我了
That's me.
樂意效勞
Happy to help.
謝謝
Thank you.
保持聯絡
I'll be in touch.
謝謝你的咖啡
Thanks for the coffee.
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
瑪德琳
Madeleine.
謝謝你能來
Thank you for coming.
喝茶嗎
Tea?
好的  謝謝
Yes, please.
把話先說清楚
Just so we're clear,
桌子下面有把槍
I have a gun pointed under the table.
正對著某個重要的東西
And it's pointed at something important.
知道了
Fair enough.
孩子們怎么樣了
How are the kids?
她們很安全
They're safe.
你只需要知道這些就行了
That's all you need to know.
你姑姑很不錯
Your aunt is a delight.
演技很好
Wonderful actress.
我必須要保護好我和孩子們
I had to do what was best for me and my kids.
我知道勞拉蕾·馬丁斯死之后
I knew that Red John was cleaning house
血腥約翰就一直在殺人滅口
after Lorelei Martins was killed.
我可不想成為下一個
I did not want to be next.
我懂的
No, I got it.
他已經試過一次要殺你了
He's already tried to kill you once.
很難從這種事中恢復過來
It's not something you ever really get over.
那到底什么事這么重要
So what's so damn important
你要把我叫出來
you had to bring me out of hiding?
我快要抓住血腥約翰了
I'm getting close to catching Red John,
我需要你的幫助
and I need your help.
我不會為了幫你而置家人于危險之中
I'm not putting my family in danger to help you.
而且我已經離開執法部門三年了
Besides, I've been out of law enforcement for three years.
我怎么幫你  我什么都不知道
How can I help you? I don't know anything.
真的嗎
Really?
我知道有件事  你已經隱瞞
Because I think you've been holding something back
很久了
for a very long time.
沒錯
Yeah, there it is.
我說對了
I'm right.
聯調局
The F.B.I.--
一直在監視我  是嗎
They've been watching me, haven't they?
如果不重要我不會來的
Please, I wouldn't be here if it weren't important.
告訴我
Tell me.
現在也沒理由不告訴你了
Well, I guess there's no reason not to tell you now.
但是你絕對不能說是我告訴你的
But obviously you did not hear this from me.
米內利掌管加調局的時候
When Minnelli was chief of the CBI,
他和聯調局局長舒爾茨達成了個協議
he struck a deal with F.B.I. Director Schultz.
舒爾茨想要什么
What did Schultz want?
她要報告
She wanted reports.
你的報告
On you.
米內利給他們了
Minnelli provided them.
米內利退休之后  這事就由我接手了
When Minnelli retired, that became a part of my job.
但是那些情報并不是給聯調局的
But the intel wasn't exactly going to the F.B.I.
我發現舒爾茨把情報轉交給
I found out that Schultz was passing it on
國土安全局了
to Homeland Security.
-是鮑勃·柯克蘭嗎  -是的
- Bob Kirkland? - Yes.
為什么
Why?
他覺得你就是血腥約翰
He thought you were Red John.
當然會如此
Of course.
國土安全局監視我多久了
How long have Homeland Security been watching me?
八  九年吧
Eight, nine years.
我當時做了我覺得正確的事
I did what I thought was best at the time.
別指望我會道歉
Don't expect me to apologize.
不  我不會要你道歉
No, no, I-I won't.
簡
Jane.
你不能告訴別人你見過我  即使是里斯本
You cannot tell anyone you saw me. Even Lisbon.
我不會的
And I won't.
我說到做到
I meant what I said.
我會殺了血腥約翰
I'm gonna kill Red John,
你就可以恢復正常生活了
and you're gonna get your life back.
希望如此
I hope so.
下一步怎么辦
So what's next?
我去見見鮑勃·柯克蘭
Well, I'm gonna go see Bob Kirkland.
我要開誠布公地
What I'm looking for is an open
和你談談
and honest dialogue.
毫無隱瞞
100% transparency.
我不知道你想從我這里得到什么
I don't know what you want from me.
我沒做過什么壞事
I didn't do anything wrong.
也許是還沒做
Maybe not yet.
但是看看你的那個地下室
But... that room in your basement.
得了吧
Come on.
你是個墮落的人
You are a depraved man.
最起碼是個戀童癖
At minimum, a pedophile.
不過說實話  這不是我們來這的原因
But frankly, that's not why we're here.
那是為了什么
Why then?
求求你告訴我  為什么
Please just tell me... why.
我把你帶來是想問幾個問題
I brought you here to ask you some questions.
什么都行  我什么都告訴你
Anything. I'll--I'll tell you anything.
那好吧  跟我說說
All right then. Tell me--
你認識我么  以前見過我嗎
Do you recognize me? Have you seen me before?
沒  我想沒有
No... I don't think so.
好的  這問題一會再說  下個問題
Okay, we'll come back to that. Next question.
什么
What?
是什么
你是血腥約翰嗎
Are you Red John?
什么
What?
你是  血腥約翰嗎
Are you... Red John?
不
No...
你是不是血腥約翰
Are you Red John?!
不是
No!
國土安全部  薩克拉門托地區辦
柯克蘭探員
Agent Kirkland?
簡  你來做什么
Jane, what are you doing here?
能跟你說句話嗎
Can I have a quick word?
不是什么私密事  你朋友可以一起
It's nothing private. Your friends can stay.
我等下過去
I'll catch up, guys.
我有一個尚未成型的推論
I have a pet theory
希望你能幫我確認或否決一下
I was hoping you could confirm or deny.
看我能力吧
I'll see what I can do.
國土安全局是不是一直在調查我
Has Homeland Security been investigating me?
是的
Yes.
你居然可以正面回答我
I'm surprised you're allowed to tell me that.
你們通常不都是喜歡保密嗎
I mean, you guys are usually so cloak and dagger.
國土安全局在調查血腥約翰的案子
Well, it's no secret that Homeland Security
已經不再是秘密
has the Red John case.
而你的名字以各種方式出現在了其中
Yeah, your name has come up in various ways.
是啊  那你們的人有沒有闖入我的辦公室
Right. So then did you guys break into my office
偷走了疑犯名單
and steal my list of suspects?
當然沒有
Absolutely not.
沒有  為什么
No? Why not?
因為我們不在乎你認為誰是血腥約翰
Because we don't care who you think Red John is.
這案子歸我們管
We have the case.
明白了
Point taken.
謝謝你抽出時間
Thanks for your time.
就這些
That's it?
是啊  我只是想確保
Yeah. I just wanted to make sure
你們不是在做無用功
you weren't on a wild goose chase,
因為不管是誰闖進了我的辦公室
because whoever it was that broke into my office,
他們偷走了假的疑犯名單
they stole a fake list of suspects.
做得好
Well played.
謝謝  我也這么覺得
Thank you. I thought so.
也許你該來為我們工作
Maybe you should come work for us.
還是算了吧
Maybe not.
需要我載你一程嗎
You need a ride somewhere?
我自己走就行  謝謝
No, I'm--I'm good, thanks.
我們應該多談談  上車吧
Well, we should talk some more. Get in the car.
我有得選嗎
Do I have a choice?
沒有
No.
那好吧
By all means...
我們再多談談吧
Let's talk some more.
讓我看看你的手機
Let me see your phone.
你不需要這樣  我就是想和你談談
Hey, you don't have to do this. I actually want to talk to you.
把手機給我
Just hand me the phone.
請系好安全帶
Seatbelt, please.
你們有沒有簡的消息
Hey, have you guys heard from Jane?
沒有
Nope.
昨天早上之后就沒見過他了
I haven't seen him since yesterday morning.
給他打電話都轉到了語音信箱
His phone just keeps on going straight to voicemail.
你能幫我定一下位嗎
Can you ping it for me?
可以啊  就是得花點時間
Sure. It'll take me a little while.
謝了  也可能什么事都沒有
Thanks. It's probably nothing.
就是這里了
And here we are.
繼續走
Keep moving.
我喜歡你對這地方做的改造
Oh, I love what you've done with the place.
來吧  我領你簡單參觀一下
Come on, I'll give you the 10-cent tour.
求你  救救我
Help me... please.
這位是理查德·海爾巴  這位是派翠克·簡
Richard Haibach, Patrick Jane.
救我
Help me.
我就是想讓你看看把你帶入
I just wanted you to see the face of the man
這場麻煩的男人的臉
who got you into this mess.
其實這事挺有趣的
It's a funny story, actually--
一場錯誤造成的鬧劇
a comedy of errors.
求求你放了我吧
Please let me go.
-不  -求你
--No. - Please.
但是別擔心  簡也有得受了
But don't worry. Jane'll get his, too.
那么  讓我們來談談真正的
So, let's talk about that real list
血腥約翰案疑犯名單吧
of Red John suspects.
我定位不到簡手機的位置
I couldn't get a hit on Jane's phone.
不管他在哪  那里都沒有手機信號
Wherever he is, he has no cell service.
可能是他打來的
That's probably him now.
我是里斯本
This is Lisbon.
你好  里斯本  知道我是誰嗎
Hello, Lisbon. Do you know who this is?
知道
Yes.
我以為你死了
I thought you were dead.
我昨天見了簡
I met with Jane yesterday.
他沒提起過
He didn't say.
我叫他不要告訴你的
I asked him not to tell you,
但是我覺得我讓他陷入麻煩了
but I think I might have gotten him into trouble.
我給他打了一天的電話
I've been trying to call him all day.
我也是
Me, too.
我昨天給了他一些線索
I gave him some information yesterday.
他有沒有說要去見誰
Did he say anything to you about who he was going to see?
沒有  他該說嗎
No. Should he have?
是的
Yes.
我們得談談
We need to talk.
因為我  簡可能做了一件
I think I might have caused Jane
非常蠢的事情
to do something very dumb.
名單這事還真有意思
Funny thing about the list.
不過  我不想告訴你
I'd... rather not share it with you.
我明白
I get it.
這一直是你個人最在意的案子
It's been your pet project for a long time.
但我也一樣
Mine, too.
你一定會和我分享的
But you will share it with me.
要不我給你一個名字作為開頭
What if I just give you one name to start?
羅伯特·柯克蘭
Robert Kirkland.
有意思
Interesting.
挺有道理的倒是
Makes sense, actually.
但完全對我沒有幫助  對吧
But it doesn't really help me with my cause, though, does it?
應該沒有  我看錯你了
No, I suppose not. I was wrong about you.
你不是血腥約翰  你和我一樣在追捕他
You're not Red John. You're hunting him, same as me.
也不太一樣
Not exactly the same.
只要能完成這件事  我可以不惜殺七個人
I'm willing to kill seven people to get the job done.
令人印象深刻啊[法語]
Touché.
你為什么不呢
Why aren't you?
因為那樣我就會成為殺人犯
Cause that would make me a murderer.
你還準備殺了血腥約翰呢
You're planning on murdering Red John.
你這說法都是沖突的
That doesn't make any sense.
好吧  我們倆有不同的處理方式
Okay, so we--we both have different approaches,
但重要的是  我們有一個相同的目標
but the important thing here is that we share a common goal.
我們可以一起合作幫助對方
We can help each other if we work together.
我對合作沒有什么興趣
I'm not interested in working together,
并且我認為你也沒有
and I doubt you are, either.
我們都想要報仇
We both want our revenge,
但只有一個人可以如愿以償
and only one of us is going to get it.
羅伯特·柯克蘭
Robert Kirkland.
我知道我應該感到驚訝  可是
I know I should be surprised, but--
但他本就挺可怕的  就這么回事
But he's a creepy guy, that's why.
他會帶簡去哪
Where would he take Jane?
可能就去他帶本杰明·馬克思去的地方
Probably the same place he took Benjamin Marx.
簡在馬克思的鞋里發現了松樹針
Jane saw a pine needle in Marx's shoe.
好像在他被殺之前
It was like he'd walked through a pine forest
曾穿過一片松樹林
before he was killed.
加州北部有一大片松樹林
Lots of pine needles in Northern California.
柯克蘭每天都要上班
Kirkland would be keeping up appearances.
每天都要到辦公室  所以
He'd be going to the office every day, so...
會在薩克拉門托百英里內的松林里嗎
Pine forest within a hundred-mile radius of Sacramento?
有可能  就目前來看只能這么推斷了
Sure, sure. If that's all we got.
頭兒
Hey, boss.
范佩爾  我需要你幫我查點東西
Van Pelt, I need you to run something for me.
位于州議會大廈百英里內  所有羅伯特·柯克蘭
Properties or businesses owned by Robert Kirkland
名下的地產或公司
within 100 miles of the Capitol...
并且要與松樹林相鄰
in close proximity to a pine forest.
羅伯特·柯克蘭
Robert Kirkland?
說來話長
It's a long story.
百英里內沒有羅伯特·柯克蘭名下的地產
Nothing for Robert Kirkland within a hundred miles.
倒是有個叫邁克爾·柯克蘭的
But there's a Michael Kirkland.
在埃爾多拉多州立公園附近有個小木屋
Owns a cabin up near El Dorado State Park.
邁克爾是他親戚嗎
Oh, is he a relative?
我不知道  可以查查看
I don't know. I can check.
好吧  把地址發我
All right, text me the address.
好的
Sure.
我們應該請求當地部門支援
We should call local authorities for backup.
不不  別叫警察
No. No. No cops.
不能讓人知道我的存在  拜托了
Nobody can know about me. Please.
好吧
Okay.
那我們要怎么辦
How do we do this?
就這么辦
That's how.
你有兄弟姐妹嗎  簡
Do you have siblings, Jane?
沒有
No.
我有個雙胞胎兄弟  邁克爾
I had a twin brother-- Michael.
我們一起長大  親密無間
We were very close growing up.
我聽說雙胞胎之間堅固的紐帶
I hear that's a strong bond.
我爸是個有施虐狂的醉鬼
And our father was a sadistic drunk.
他常把我們和我母親打得家都不認識
He beat the crap out of us and our mother.
最后把她打得實在受不了了
Beat her till she couldn't take it anymore.
-她走了  -用剃須刀片把自己了結了
- She left? - With a razor blade.
從那以后
After that,
就只剩我和邁克爾了
it was just me and Michael.
他只能事事仰仗著我
I was all he had.
你比較堅強
You were the stronger one.
是的
Yeah.
后來我長大了  離開了家
Uh, I grew up. I got away.
可是邁克爾不行
But Michael couldn't do it.
他留在了家里
He stayed at home
眼看著我爸喝酒喪了命
and watched our father drink himself to death.
可是有其父  必有其子
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
你說對了
You're right.
邁克爾也開始酗酒
Michael turned to the bottle,
好像他必須以酒為生
drank like his life depended on it.
我付錢讓他去治療
I paid for treatments.
帶他參加戒酒互助會
I took him to meetings.
毫無效果
Nothing worked.
然后呢
Until?
有一天他遇見了某個人
Until one day he met someone,
那個人可以拯救他
a man who could help him.
何止是某個人  簡直是救世主
More than a man. A savior.
對  就是血腥約翰
Yeah. Red John.
他要的回報不多
He only asked for a few simple things in return.
忠誠和犧牲
Devotion and sacrifice.
邁克爾越陷越深
Michael drifted further and further away
直到有一天他不知所蹤了
until one day he was gone.
我再也沒有見過他
I never saw him again.
你認為血腥約翰把你兄弟殺了
You think Red John killed your brother.
沒錯
Yes.
我一直沒找到他
I never found him,
但我心里清楚
but in my heart, I know.
看我胡扯些什么呢
Look at me blab.
你又不是我的心理醫生
I-I... you're not my therapist.
我不是帶你來這兒聊天的
I didn't bring you here to talk.
請告訴我嫌犯都有誰
Please tell me who the suspects are.
不行
No.
隨你便
Have it your way.
你知道我會拷問你的吧
You understand, I'm gonna have to torture you.
你不像是能承受肉體痛苦的人
You don't seem like someone who deals well with physical pain.
不怎么行
Uh, not particularly.
那就給我個名字
A name then.
不行
I can't do it.
好吧
Fine.
天吶
God!
好  好  好
Okay, okay, okay.
你必須明白
You... you--you have to understand,
從感情角度上出發
this is hard for me...
這對我很艱難
Emotionally.
我還從沒跟任何人透露過這幾個人的名字
I've never said any of these names out loud to anyone.
給我個名字
A name.
尚海沃
Turtmee.
名為布瑤
First name--Don.
布瑤·尚海沃
Don Turtmee?
不要傷害我
"Don't hurt me."
受不了你
You got me.
那個  我可得...
Why, I oughta...
把手舉起來
Put your hands in the air!
把手舉到我們能看得到的地方
Keep 'em where we can see 'em!
簡  你沒事吧
Jane, you all right?
再好沒有了
Oh, never better.
我沒事  好得很
I'm just fine. Dandy.
還好我們來了
Ooh! Thanks to us.
你竟然傻到一個人來
You were foolish to come here alone.
其實你很開心吧
You taking pleasure in this?
別誤會了
Don't get me wrong.
你就是個惹事兒精
You are a pain in the ass.
謝了
Well, thank you.
不過我不希望你出事
But I wouldn't want anything bad to happen to you,
尤其當事出于我的時候
especially when it would be my fault.
現在你肯定覺得問心無愧了吧
Well, I'm sure your conscience is clear now.
沒錯  所以別來煩我了
It is. Now leave me alone.
下次你再找我
Next time I hear from you,
最好是告訴我血腥約翰已經死了
you better be telling me Red John is dead.
說好了
Deal.
一言為定
That is a deal.
謝謝你  瑪德琳
Thank you, Madeleine.
不客氣  派翠克
You're welcome, Patrick.
祝你好運
Good luck.
里斯本
Lisbon...
-你自己沒問題吧  -是的
- You good here? - Yeah.
現在可以請求支援了
You can call for that backup now.
我會找你算賬的
You'll pay for this!
我不會饒了你的  這事兒都怪你
I won't forget! This is on you!
你真的沒事嗎
You sure you're all right?
名單縮短到五個人了
The list is down to five names.
這就更好查了
That is a very manageable number.
我怎么就沒這感覺
Somehow that doesn't reassure me.
到了最后時刻了  里斯本
We're in the home stretch, Lisbon.
伙計們
Hey, guys.
那個
So, uh,
看來我誤會你了
looks like I got it wrong about you.
是啊  你是誤會他了
Yeah. Looks like you did.
沒事  孰能無過呢
Ah, it's all right. We all make mistakes.
我說
I mean, a...
竟然會是國土安全部的探員
a homeland security agent?
真是想不到  是吧
Who would have thought, right?
不包括我
Not me.
剩下就是一堆管轄權的麻煩事兒了
It's gonna be a jurisdictional cluster-bomb.
不過我們會先把他扣留在縣里
But we'll book him first at county.
過幾天再把他轉押到
In a few days he'll get transferred
聯邦看守所
to a federal detention center.
-我想和他聊幾句  -沒問題
- I'd like to talk to him for a sec. - Sure.
簡
Hey, Jane.
既往不咎了吧
No hard feelings, huh?
當然了  既往不咎
No. No hard feelings.
里斯本
Lisbon.
你要是還有話要說
If you have anything else to say,
最好現在就說
now would be the time.
我掌握了點東西
Oh, I might know some things.
不過現在說不合適
But this isn't the best place to talk.
到時候來見我
Come see me sometime.
會的
I will.
你會堅持到底吧
Are you gonna finish this thing?
會的
Yes.
里斯本來電話了
Hey. Lisbon called.
他們今晚不回局里了
They're not coming back into the office tonight.
-知道了  -你也可以走了
- Okay. - You can probably go, too.
-其他人都走了  -是啊
- There's nobody else here. - Sure.
你換衣服了
Did you change?
你說這件舊衣服嗎
What, this old thing?
等等  這是什么
Wait. What's this?
像是酒店房卡
It looks like a hotel room key.
等一下  你不會是
Wait. You didn't, did you?
是的  訂了蜜月套房
I did. The honeymoon suite.
卡佩羅夫人在照看本
Mrs. Capello is watching Ben.
太棒了  謝謝
That's amazing. Thank you.
我都開始以為...
You know, I was beginning to think--
我知道你怎么想的
I know what you thought.
我是不是瘋了
And am I crazy?
是的
Yes.
別想太多了  韋恩
You shouldn't think so much, Wayne.
走吧
Come on.
當我不存在
Don't mind me.
我和他談談
Let me speak to him.
怎么了  你怎么來了
What's going on? What are you doing here?
其實你的分析非常正確  鮑勃
You hit the nail on the head, Bob.
關于什么
About what?
執法部門內部確實存在一個強大的組織
There is a powerful organization within law enforcement.
不過比你以為的更大
But it's a lot bigger than you thought.
不光是高層參與了
It's not just the big boys, either.
像我這種級別低的也可以進
They even let lower level guys like me in.
我知道你什么意思了
I know what you're doing.
我們已經盯你很久了
We've had our eye on you for a long time.
我們不過想幫個忙  僅此而已
We just want to help. It's what we do.
怎么幫
Help me how?
仔細聽好了
Listen to me closely.
這是個安全屋的地址
That's the address of a safe house.
從這兒往正東兩英里
It's 2 miles due east of here.
你到了那兒  會有人接應你
When you get there, someone will contact you,
給你錢  新的身份  還有衣服
Get you some money, I.D., clothes.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
快  鮑勃
Come on, Bob.
下車
Get out of the van.
跑吧
Start running.
就在這兒動手吧
Just do it here.
我更希望你跑
Actually, I'd prefer it if you ran.
你知道的  規矩是這樣
You know... protocol.
柯克蘭探員意圖逃跑
Agent Kirkland tried to escape.
你別無他法  只能將其擊斃
You had no choice but to use deadly force.
明白了嗎
Do you understand?
老虎老虎
Tiger tiger.